Aditya Lamba

Tempe, AZ • 602-582-82195 • adityalamba19@gmail.com • LinkedIn • GitHub • (Authorized to work in the US)

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 4+ years of professional experience, offering expertise in front end development, web development, user engagement, and product optimization. Proven track-record of developing products with an emphasis on improving application efficiency and user experience. Expertise in JavaScript, TypeScript, React and Angular.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Bash Shell

Front-End: React, Angular, Redux, Figma, Bootstrap, D3.js, JSON, RxJS, DOM, Web APIs

Database: MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, SQL

Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, CI/CD, Postman, Node.js, Express.js, Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Coalfield Development | West Virginia, U.S.A

Full Stack Engineer Intern

May 2023 - Present

- Oversaw the development of a \$150k application, architecting backend solution to support 500 early-stage users and creating a responsive web design, achieving 90% user satisfaction.
- Created responsive web designs using Figma and dynamic React Interfaces with Material UI components enhancing user engagement by 30% and increasing web accessibility standards by 40%.
- Utilized React Hooks and Redux for efficient state management, optimizing application performance by 25%
- Developed MongoDB schemas and REST APIs with Node.js & Express.js, ensuring seamless integration with front-end.

Infosys Ltd | Pune, India

Senior Software Developer

April 2020 - December 2021

- Developed a highly scalable, cross-browser compatible web application using Angular, TypeScript for service disruption tracking, which contributed to saving \$100k by boosting query resolution.
- Implemented bulk upload processes by using OpenCV in JavaScript, enabling the efficient handling of up to 50,000 consignments per upload through advanced algorithmic solutions.
- Developed and streamlined a CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, integrated with Docker for containerization and Kubernetes for orchestration, achieving seamless deployment across 7 applications.
- Collaborated on 5 Agile Methodology projects, addressing complex issues in real-time with clients and development teams.

Infosys Ltd | Pune, India

Software Developer

May 2018 - April 2020

- Enhanced application security by implementing Oath 2.0 authentication with Okta and configuring Angular HTTP interceptors to fortify security protocols.
- Achieved 85% code coverage and fixed issues by writing unit test cases using Karma and Jasmine for five applications.
- Developed user interface of HR Portal using JavaScript framework in test driven development, increasing user engagement by 20%.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

December 2023

Arizona State University, Arizona, U.S.A

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SRM University, India

May 2018

PROJECTS

COVID Analyzer (Master's Project Data Visualization) GitHub | Live Page

August 2022 - December 2022

• Visualizes the pandemic's impact on New York counties through six responsive, interactive graphs using D3.js, Python, and Ajax, offering critical insights for healthcare and policy decision-making.

NYC Taxi Graph Analysis GitHub

January 2023 - May 2023

- Utilized Docker, Kubernetes, and PostgreSQL to deploy graph data processing, implementing node and BFS algorithm.
- Proficiently set up Docker containers, integrated neo4j GDS plugin and executed graph analysis in distributed setup.